RAWAND FARHAD









REDACTED # ME@RAWAND.DEV # III LINKEDIN.COM/IN/RAWANDKURDY

Summary

I believe with constant trying and putting the right amount of effort anything is accomplishable. I have great experience, lots of energy, a bit of that "vision thing" and I'm not afraid to start from the beginning.

Skill Highlights

- Scrum methodology
- Performance and scalability
- Fast learner

- Optimization
- **API** Design
- Teamwork

Experience

More Details on LinkedIn

Programmer Assistant - 10/2019 - Present University of Human Development, Iraq

- Teaching and Assisting Practical Classes.
- Including but not limited to Networks, OOP, Algorithms, Cyber Security, etc.

Software Developer, IT Technician - 06/2012 - 09/2019 Self Employed, Iraq

- Application Development Freelancing.
- Troubleshooting Computer/Communication Devices issues.

Software Engineer - 02/2018 - 07/2018

KnowledgeFlow BVBA, Belgium [Remotely]

- Software testing and debugging.
- Training and working with Microsoft LUIS.
- Developing a Chatbot with Microsoft Bot Builder and connecting with KF API.
- Developed with JavaScript, NodeJS, and other Frameworks.
- Worked as a team, as part of Erasmus Blended AIM [2018].

Tech Writer, Developer, Moderator - 03/2009 - 01/2011 MeNokia.com, Internet

- Published tech articles on daily basis.
- Decompiled Symbian applications and translated apps from various languages to English/Arabic.
- Released custom firmwares for Nokia phones without having any prior professional training.

Education

Bachelor of Science: Computer Science - 2018 - Grade (A+)

University of Human Development, IQ

Student of the Year 2017, Student of the Semester 2016, Winner of ENGL Competition 2015

Technical Skills

More Details on LinkedIn

Programming Languages

• Java, JavaScript, Python, Golang, TypeScript

Technologies, Frameworks

- NodeJS, REST, GraphQL, gRPC, JWT
- React Native, ReduxJS, Jitsi Meet, ExpressJS, Socket.IO, MikroORM, Gqlgen, Chi

Databases, Data Models

- MySQL, SQLite, MongoDB
- JSON, YAML, CSV

Version Control, Orchestration

- Git, Git Modules with GitHub, Bitbucket or Gitlab
- Docker, Docker Compose, Kubernetes (K8)

Others

- CI/CD (DevOPS) with Gitlab, Code Generation with Golang
- Shell Scripting

Additional Skills

Languages

- English Fluent. IELTS Certified CEFR C1 Level
- Arabic Fluent.
- Kurdish Native.

Driving License

Private Iraqi driving license.

References

References available on request.